Preliminary Guide to the Raul Ruiz film and videotape collection, 1960-1996 RL.01119
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Raul Ruiz film and videotape collection
1960-1996
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Ruiz, Raul, 1941-
RL.01119
5.4 Linear Feet
Acclaimed Chilean filmmaker now living in exile in France. Feature and short films in Spanish, French, Italian, and English. Includes reels of audio and video film. One set of videocassettes contains Ruiz' interpretation of Dante's Inferno, produced for television by the BBC. Some films deal with social conditions in Chile during the 1960s and 1970s. Others are fabulist films set in various places around the world. Also included are use copies of the collection in DVD and VHS formats.
166 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Also, original audiovisual materials are CLOSED to patron use. Use copies are available in the collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Raul Ruiz film and videotape collection were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a deposit in 1996.
Biographical Note
Acclaimed Chilean filmmaker now living in exile in France.
Collection Overview
Feature and short films in Spanish, French, Italian, and English. Includes reels of audio and video film. One set of videocassettes contains Ruiz' interpretation of Dante's Inferno, produced for television by the BBC. Some films deal with social conditions in Chile during the 1960s and 1970s. Others are fabulist films set in various places around the world. Also includes 5 DVD use copies and 3 VHS use copies.
Independent filmmakers -- Chile; Motion picture producers and directors; Independent filmmakers -- France; Foreign films; Political refugees -- Chile; Chile -- Social life and customs; Chile -- Social conditions; Ruiz, Raul, 1941-
- Accession 1996 (1996-0126), 158 items
  Scope and Contents note
  Feature and short films in Spanish, French, Italian, and English. Includes reels of audio and video film. One set of videocassettes contains Ruiz' interpretation of Dante's Inferno, produced for television by the BBC. Some films deal with social conditions in Chile during the 1960s and 1970s. Others are fabulist films set in various places around the world.
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Original audiovisual materials are CLOSED to patron use. Use copies are available for some items in the collection.
  - Treasure Island (English), 7 reels, 600 meters each, 35 mm. film; Approx. 2 hrs., 10 mins.
    (other title: L'isle au tresor). Copie 0. Screening reels -- ready to view.
  - L'autel de l'amitie', 1 reel, 600 m., 16 mm. film
    (The altar of friendship)
  - Viaggio clandestino (Italian), 2 reels, 300 m. each, 16 mm. film
    (Clandestine voyage.) Copie 0.
  - Nadie dijo nada (Spanish, 1971 ), 2 reels, 500 m. each, 16 mm. film
    (Nobody said anything.) Probably only copy in existence.
  - La vocation suspendue (French)
    (The suspended career.) Magnetic sound. Copie mixage: image and magnetic sound mixed; basically ready to view.
    - Canister 1, 2 reels, circa 250 m. each, 16 mm.
      copie mixage
    - Canister 2, 2 reels, circa 250 m. each, 16 mm.
    - Canister 3, 2 reels, circa 250 m. each, 16 mm.
      On cover color film, Copie 0
  - Paya y talla (Spanish), One canister: one reel, 240 meters, 16 mm. film; about 25 minutes.
    Copie 0
  - Hubert Bals (name of painter)
    Incomplete film on original inventory (probably means in process of being edited, etc.)
    - Canister 1, All sound: 5 reels ("1988") plus one image reel
    - Canister 2, All sound: 7 reels
    - Canister 2a, 2 reels, one image, one sound
    - Canister 3, 2 reels, probably "double band" -- i.e., sound and image? One may be a sound edit (only sound)
    - Canister (no number), 8 reels, some sound, some image (separately on each reel)
  - L'autel de l'amitie Security mixage, One reel, 600 m., magnetic sound, 16 mm. film
  - Sotelo, One reel, 200 m., 16 mm. film
    Copie 0 Copie optical but looks like it also has optical sound.
  - Payadores (documentary)(Spanish)
    (The hay-makers?)
    - Canister 1, 2 separate reels, 250 m., sound; 250 m. image, 16 mm.
    - Canister 2 material pour montage:, 7 small reels, 200 m., image, 16 mm.
    - Canister 3, 1 reel, 500 m. magnetic sound, 16 mm.
    - Reels of magnetic sound, 8 reels
      Comidas 1-4; Payadores 1-5, missing #3, or boxes are mislabeled?
  - Voyage d'une main (French), 2 reels, one sound, one image, 250 m. ea., 16 mm. film
    (Journey of a hand)
    - Image reel: Copie travail plus commentaire and 1986
    - Sound reel: Copie securite
  - Les divisions de la nature (French), 1 reel, 16 mm, sound and image mixed
    (Alternate title Chambord.) Part of a French series on castles in France, called Un homme, un chateau. Copie 0. Distribution copy: ready for viewing.
  - El Infierno 2 (Spanish)
    (alternate title, Basta la palabra). TV series on Dante.
    - Canister Bob.1, 2 reels, sound and image separate
    - Canister Bob. 1
      - copie travail, version synchro, 612 m.
      - son direct, 1 reel (sound only)
      - copie travail bob. 1, 1 reel (image and sound?)
    - Canister Number II, 2 reels, Bob. 2 on each, probably sound and image separate
      Probably working edit copy (in progress)
    - Canister Bob. 3, 2 reels, probably sound and image
    - Canister Bob. 4, 2 reels, sound and image, Bob. 4 on each
      Working print (in progress)
    - Canister Bob. 5, 2 reels, sound and image separate
      Also labeled on cover Fin- Infierno 2.
    - Canister (not numbered), 2 reels, Fin/Direct1/Bob.2 written on each. One image, one sound.
  - Sound reels from El Infierno II. unfinished film 1991, 26 reels (original list said 25) of sound (magnetic tape)
  - Sound reels (FX) from English television version of Infierno (?)., 6 sound reels
  - La telenovela errante, 4 canisters: one is labeled #5 -- by mistake?
    (The [wandering?] soap opera)
    - Canister 1, 2 reels, 350 m. each, sound and image, 16 mm.
      (NOTE: film very loose, unwinding off of core)
    - Canister 2, 2 reels, 350 m. each, sound and image, 16 mm.
    - Canister 3, 2 reels, 350 m. each, sound and image, 16 mm.
    - Canister 4, 2 reels, 350 m. each, sound and image, 16 mm.
      (NOTE: film unwinding off of core; film is getting bent)
  - Paisajes (Spanish), 9 canisters, one reel each, 120 m. each, 35 mm.
    (Landscapes.) Negative copy. 1989 on some canisters.
  - Reels, 2 sets of reels
    Canisters labeled 1-6 and Rollo 1-Rollo 3.
  - Las Meninas (Spanish), 120 m. total?, 16 mm. film
    Film about the painter Velasquez.
    - Canister 1, one reel, mislabeled A propos de Nice
    - Canister 2, one reel
      304, negative copy.
    - Canister 3, 2 reels, sound and image (waiting to be mixed?)
    - Canister 4, Contains one reel, image only
  - Realismo socialista (documentary, Spanish), 2500 m. magnetic sound, 16 mm film. 2500 m. magnetic image, 16 mm. film
  - Double band, Sound and image on one reel, in two bands.
  - Large canisters, 11 canisters, 8 with 2 reels each, but three with 3, 4, and 7 rolls of film, respectively.
    Arrangement note
    (canisters are labeled with number of items in each)
  - Small canister, Contains one reel (probably sound)
  - Small canister, 2 reels
  - Magnetic tape reels of sound., 2 reels
  - Le borgne (French)
    (The one-eyed person)
    - Canister, 2 reels, 300 m. each, image, 16 mm.
    - Canisters, 3 canisters contain 4 reels, 300 m. each, magnetic sound, 16 mm.
  - Classification des plantes (French), 3 reels, 60 m. each, 1 image and 2 sound, 16 mm.
    (The classification of plants)
  - Le meurtre (French), 2 reels, 30 m. each, 1 image, 1 sound, 16 mm.
    (The murder? could also be The shame, The crime)
- Use copies, 1 boxes
  Box contains 5 DVD and 3 VHS use copies of films in the collection
  - DVD use copies, 5 DVDs (Box 1)
    - Il Viaggio clandestino (Box 1)
    - Les Divisions de la nature (Box 1)
    - Paya y talla (Box 1)
    - Sotelo (Box 1)
    - L'Autel de l'amitie (Box 1)
  - VHS use copies, 3 videocassettes
    - Sotelo and Paya y talla (Box 1)
    - Il Viaggio clandestino (Box 1)
    - Les Divisions de la nature and L'autel de l'amitie (Box 1)